Nuha S. Taha

OBJECTIVE

Seasoned and results-orientated IT professional specialized in websites and web applications testing with extensive experience in project management. Over 10 years of experience with key international clients and proven ability in both client facing and technical roles. I have outstanding testing and quality assurance capabilities, service delivery and client relationship management, system engineering and project management skills. My objectives are to be a part of team where:

- I can extensive computer information system knowledge seeking for a position in well establish strong methodologies in the IT fields.
- Discover a new technologies and experiences.
- I can grow with the organization I am working with.
- Improve managerial and communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VARDOT

June 2014 — July 2015

QA Team Lead

Responsibilities and duties:

- Building the QA department.
- Managing the Quality resources and activities.
- Set the QA process and strategic, including creating QA Plans.
- Prepare QA checklists and conduct QA checks on company products (Drupal)
- Working closely with management and departments to review Company projects and objectives.
- Designed and created all test plans, test specifications and test cases for the QA department.
- Providing analysis, reports and status of all projects in test, bug trends, postponed bugs and milestone progress.
- Creating sprints and tasks on JIRA and monitor project activities.
- Analyze data sets for validity and consistency.
- Meet development milestones and business objectives on schedule.

ESKADENIA Software

March 2013 — May 2014

QA Team Lead - Insurance Department

Responsibilities and duties:

 Responsible for management of all Quality Assurance functions include planning, strategy & testing execution.

- Review and Approval of the testing strategy, approach, and plans.
- Provide formal sign-off on all testing deliverable and testing events.
- Review of testing results and defects to determine/assess impact to overall project plan and implementation schedule.
- Ensure tractability of test cases to requirements, working with the project Business Analyst to ensure all requirements are tested.
- Develop and implement test plans.
- Escalate the issues in products to top managers.
- Prepare the Agenda for the meetings.
- Send Status reports (Daily, Weekly..etc) to the top management.
- Act as the single point of contact between the development and testers for iterations, testing and deployment activities.
- Assign tasks to all QA team members and ensure that all of them have sufficient work in the projects.
- Coordinating with the development department to ensure required test platforms are available
- Track and report upon testing activities, including testing results, test cases coverage, required resources, defects discovered and their status, performance baselines..etc.
- Ensure content and structure of all testing documents is documented and maintained.
- Identify training requirements and forward it to the project managers.
- Manage the automation testing process.
- Attend weekly Team Leaders meeting.
- Motivate team members.

Tanasuk Technologies

June 2011 — March 2013

Senior QA

Responsibilities and duties:

- Supervising, Leading & Assigning tasks to team members and support them.
- Writing Functional Specifications
- Prepared Test Cases.
- Conducted Integration, System, Functional, GUI, Regression, Smoke, Database, User-Acceptance & Mobile testing.
- Internet Tools testing (Sitecore, Arezzo, Sharepoint).
- Gathering and analyzing Business Requirements.
- Understand the SDLC thoroughly and is familiar with both the *waterfall* and *agile* software processes.
- Wrote or edited multiple documents, including SRS reports, plans, & proposals.

Dot Jo

May 2010 — June 2011

Senior QA

Responsibilities and duties:

- QA engineer position but focused on manual website UI, Functional & End User testing.
- Executes and develops Manual, Functionality, Black Box, Integration, Regression Testing and report results/defects on Mantis (Defect Tracking System).
- Provides input to estimates of project resources and timelines.

- Works closely with technical and non-technical staff including development and producers.
- QA for small & large projects under broad supervision.
- Creation & Execution of test cases.
- Gathering and analyzing Business Requirements.
- Review project technical documents and provide input as required.

Aspire Services

December 2005 — May 2010

Software QA Analyst

Responsibilities and duties:

- Supervising, Leading & Assigning tasks to team members and support them.
- Creating, reviewing and checking Test Cases and Test sets for testing preparation.
- Development, Design & Preparing Test Plan.
- Writing/Checking defect reports.
- Execute Manual, Functionality, Black Box, Gray box, Integration, Regression Testing and report results in Mercury Quality Center (Tracking system) for follow up.
- Mobile Testing (iPhone, BlackBerry, Android)
- Internet Tools testing (Content Management Systems, GCMS)
- Tracking of reported problems and defects
- Writing Business and Activity diagrams analysis.
- Preparing the daily/weekly testing reports.
- Quality Technical Supervisor on several projects.
- Project schedule and management preparation resources, time and efficiency factors).
- Direct Communication and reporting issues with client (Weight Watchers Company).
- Monitoring people by organizing the work and environment to work as effectively as possible.
- Prepare end of project signoff, statistics and weakness vs. strongest points.
- Reporting test results with clear and standardized format (or ally and written).
- Responsible for training the new employee for QA (quality analyst) and CS (Customer services) departments.

QUALIFICATIONS

§ MS Excel/Word/PowerPoint/FrontPage/Outlook/Project/Access/Visio

- § Using Mercury Quality Center
- § Using Mantis, TFS, Jira
- § Good Knowledge in Drupal
- § Good Knowledge in Sitecore (CMS)
- § Good Knowledge in Sharepoint.
- § Using Visual Source Safe.
- § Using Fiddler.
- § Using G/CMS Tools
- § Toad for Oracle (Used for Database testing)
- § Good knowledge in UML uses case.
- § Adobe (Photoshop CS 4, Illustrator CS 4).
- § HTML coding/CSS.
- § Agile & Waterfall Projects.

- § Quality Control.
- § SCRUM.
- § CMMI
- § Proposal Writing.
- § Content Management.
- § Conference Management.
- § Client Servicing.
- § Time & Project Management.
- § Mobile Apps Testing.
- § SEO & Online Marketing.
- § Good written and oral communication skills
- § Good problem analysis & troubleshooting skills
- § Good report writing skills
- § Experience working with off-shore teams
- § Knowledge of methods and processes used in quality assurance
- § Strong multi-tasking and problem solving skills along with ability to meet aggressive deadlines
- § Career-minded, mature, disciplined.
- § Works effectively under pressure; both as an individual or a team men ber.
- § Very high sense of commitment, obligation and responsibility.
- § Good Command of English: spoken & written.
- § April 2014 Successfully finished PMP Courses (which took place in Method)

EDUCATION

Computer Information System

2000 - 2004

Applied Science University

REFERENCES

References available upon request.